# **Tushar Gautam**

Boulder, Colorado tushar.rishav@gmail.com

MS, Computer Science

LinkedIn @gautamtushar Github @tushar-rishav

#### **SUMMARY**

Proclivity towards problem-solving with about 6 years of full-stack product and platform development. At Anoki, I've led a team which enabled AI-powered, contextually richer Ad biddings for SSAI. Contributions have been full-stack product development, scalable recording of video streams, and setup reliable ML pipeline for processing large-scale video datasets. Also built a Recommendation service for Anoki TV channels, core platform libraries, and setup infrastructure services.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Engineer - Anoki Inc

Mountain View, CA, USA | June 2023 - Current

- Project Lead for a full-stack product, driving major business revenue with contextually richer Ad biddings for SSAI.
- Built recording service for 500+ live TV channels having auto scale-out capabilities.
- Designed a reliable ML pipeline for generating embeddings from a large-scale datasets, spanning GPU cluster.
- Developed recommendation system for OTT application, enhanced user experience with hyper-personalization of TV channels.
- Developed core platform libraries for Config Management and Service Discovery mechanisms based on Consul and Kubernetes.
- Implemented GraphQL backends for Content Management & Scheduling to on-board new content providers.
- Managed infrastructure setup for HAProxy, Presto, Superset, Consul, Kubernetes, and AWS services.
- Trained teams on Git, and Presto.

### Software Engineer Intern - PayPal

New York City, NY, USA | May 2022 - August 2022

Added static type safety for GraphQL resolvers based on a schema-first design philosophy, increasing code maintainability.

# **Software Engineer - LG Ads**

Bangalore, KA, India | June 2017 — June 2021

- 5x latency optimization for a large-scale fingerprint distribution network for Audio Content Recognition system.
- Lead projects in the realm of core platform development with monitoring, logging and distributed storage infrastructure.
- Setup and managed key infrastructure projects: load balancers, and large-scale Spark cluster.

## Google Summer of Code - Python Software Foundation

Bangalore, KA, India | April 2016 - August 2016

- Built interactive static code analysis tool with 97% code coverage for frontend and, 100% for backend.
- Presented a workshop on "Guide to open-source contributions using Git and CI/CD" at EuroPython conference in Bilbao, Spain.

Tech Stack exposure: Go, Python, NodeJS, TypeScript, C++, Svelte/SvelteKit, AngularJS, Kubernetes, ML Flow, Airflow, Protobuf, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Consul, Presto, Superset, HaProxy, GraphQL, Prometheus, Grafana and AWS - Mediaconvert, S3, Cloudfront, RDS, Bash, Docker, HDFS, Ceph, Spark, Mesos, Kafka, Ansible, Jenkins, EtcD, Linux IP table, HTML, CSS, Git, TravisCI, Karma, Mocha, ChaiJS, Test Driven Development.

## PATENT

· System For Contextual Searching Using Text Search Terms

Feb 2024

#### **EDUCATION**

# M.S, Computer Science, University of Colorado, Boulder

Aug 2021 - May 2023

B.Tech, Production Engineering, National Institute of Technology, Trichy

July 2013 - May 2017

# **RELEVANT COURSES**

Advanced Data Structures and Algorithms, Network Systems, Operating Systems, Distributed Systems, NLP and Deep Learning, Database, Blockchain

#### **PROJECTS**

- Image Defogging using DDPM: A generative model leveraging U-Net and a linear noise scheduler to enhance the Foggy CityScapes dataset. May 2023
- Distributed Config Deployment: Implementation of fault-tolerant distributed system based on a spanning tree topology. [ Github ], [ YouTube ] Dec 2022
- Named Entity Recognition: Fine-tuned LLMs on a medical dataset achieving F1 score of 0.91.

Dec 2021

- SemEval-2022 Task-4: Detecting patronizing and condescending language with fine-tuning LLMs, ranked 1st. [Github] Dec 2021
- GitMate: Contributed bug fixes and new features for ranking bugs in GitMate an automated code review and issue triaging platform for GitHub projects. 2016